(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-pro-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
差し入れを贈ってくださった皆様、本当にありがとうございます！
To everyone who sent gifts, thank you so much!
ここに宣言します！
I declare here and now!
セブンスホイッスル
Seventh Whistle!
ひとつ
First...
病める時も
In sickness...
健やかなる時もずっと
And in health, always...
愛を歌い続けることを
To continue singing of love,
堂々と誓います
I proudly vow.
ふたつ
Second...
トークだとかダンスももっと追求します
I'll pursue my talk and dance even more.
みっつ
Third...
ずっと推してもらえるアイドルになってみせます
I'll prove I can be an idol you'll want to support forever.
よっつめ
Fourth...
不安な未来も私が照らすんだ
I will illuminate even the anxious future.
それでも落ち込んじゃう日は
But on days when you feel down,
思い出しているよ みんなのその笑顔 その声
I'm remembering everyone's smiles and voices.
Happy Lucky Seven 革命
Happy Lucky Seven Revolution!
Sunday Monday
この先ずっと一緒だよね
From now on we're together forever, right?
約束
It's a promise.
ほらね 笑う門に空来る
See, Sora comes to those who smile.
Happy Birthday
毎日がほら
Look, every day is...
Tuesday Wednesday Lucky Day
生まれ変わっても迷わずに
Even if I'm reborn, without hesitation,
君だけのアイドルになるよ
I'll become an idol just for you.
何度も見つけてね
Find me again and again,
セブンスホイッスル
Seventh Whistle.
いつつ
Fifth...
アイドルとは時にあざとくがお決まりと
That 'idols must be cutesy at times' is the rule...
誰かが言ってたけど
Someone said that, but...
うまくできないので
I can't do it very well...
むっつめ
Sixth...
私からお願い聞いて
Listen to a request from me.
相思相愛 推し変なんてしないでよね
It's mutual love, so don't you dare change your oshi, okay?
私を見て
Look at me!
Happy Lucky Seven 革命
Happy Lucky Seven Revolution!
Sunday Monday
1st year 2019
2nd year 2020
3rd year 2021
4th year 2022
5th year 2023
6th year 2024
7th year 2025
Are You Ready?
Ten!
Nine!
Eight!
Seven!
Six!
Five!
Four!
Three!
Two!
One!
みんなー！
Everyone!
楽しさに釣られ
Lured in by the fun,
うっかり探したら
when I inadvertently searched for it,
知らないあれやこれ
this and that which I didn't know,
巡り会った
I came across.
大変な挑戦も
Even difficult challenges,
のんびり休息も
and leisurely breaks,
支え合って想い
supporting each other, our feelings
伝染した
spread out.
未開拓でも
Even if it's unexplored territory,
前を向いて
looking forward,
小さな行進重ねた
we stacked up small steps forward.
絶えず途切れない
Constantly uninterrupted,
笑い声の中を
within the laughter,
進んでこう
let's move forward.
さあ教えて ほら全部
Come on, tell me, look, everything.
何回時計の針
No matter how many times the clock's hands
グルグル回っても
spin round and round,
話を聞くよ
I'll listen to your story.
まだまだ終わらない
It's not over yet,
この夢がきっとずっと
this dream will surely, always,
永遠に褪せることのない
never fading for all eternity,
時間を君にくれる
give you that time.
訪れた先で
At the place we visited,
歓迎増えていく
the welcome continues to grow.
すれ違った風に
To the wind that passed by,
聞いたみたい
it seemed to ask.
そして世界中を
And making the whole world
巻き込んで大行進
involved in a grand march,
一人また一人
one person, and then another,
加わった
joined in.
直感だよって
Saying 'It's intuition,'
価値を探す
we search for value.
双眼鏡覗いても分からない
Even looking through binoculars, you won't understand.
迷っているのも
Even being lost,
それが醍醐味なんだって
saying 'That is the real thrill,'
言っていいよ
it's okay to say it.
ねえ たくさんの思い出を
Hey, holding tight to many memories
零さないように抱きしめて
so they don't spill,
花束を大切に
carrying the bouquet carefully,
運び続ける
we will continue to carry it.
出会えた瞬間に
At the moment we met,
どんな場所だよって
saying 'What kind of place is this?'
さっと広げ
quickly spreading it out,
見せつけていこう
let's show it off.
次は君のもとへ
Next, to where you are.
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
さあ教えて　ほら全部
Come on, tell me everything.
何回時計の針　ぐるぐる回っても
No matter how many times the clock's hands spin around.
話を聞くよ
I'll listen to your story.
あなたなら終わらない
If it's you, it won't end.
この夢がきっと　ずっと永遠に
This dream will surely, forever, eternally...
褪せることのない時を
...give you a time that never fades.
君にくれる
I'll give it to you.
La la la...
みんな掛け声頼むよ！
Everyone, I'm counting on your cheers!
夢に詰め込んだ
Packed into a dream,
夢はくしゃくしゃで
the dream is all crumpled up.
勇気がいるけど
It takes courage, but...
君にだけは見せるよ
...I'll show it only to you.
ほらColor
Look, Color!
一緒に行けるなら
If we can go together,
Vividな街も
even the vivid town...
渡してく
...we'll cross through.
深呼吸して分かったこと
What I realized after taking a deep breath.
想定外で笑っちゃうくらい
It's so unexpected it makes me laugh.
大好きは単純なまま行こう
Let's keep our love simple as we go.
楽しかった意味を
Even when the meaning of fun...
うまくいかない時だって
...doesn't go well sometimes.
直球ルート　明日の教科書
A direct route, tomorrow's textbook.
水に流したら　何だってやれそうだ
If we wash it away, feels like we can do anything.
落書きの
Inside the doodles...
中光ってた想いを
...the feelings were shining.
君とこうして話せたなんて
That I could talk with you like this...
嘘みたいだな　もっと
...feels like a lie. More!
また書いて消して
Writing again and erasing.
未知の展開も悪くはないよね
Unknown developments aren't bad either, right?
酸いも甘いも
The sour and the sweet.
集めた魔法　しようかな
Shall I use the magic I collected?
成長できるかな
I wonder if I can grow.
共に街を抜け出そう
Let's break out of this town together.
何度増えても
No matter how many times it grows,
守るから
I will protect it.
いつでも
Always.
何回ずっと
How many times? Forever.
大好きは単純なまま行こう
Let's keep our love simple as we go.
楽しかった意味を
The meaning of our fun times,
一瞬全部を
every single moment,
昨日よりも加速してる
is accelerating more than yesterday.
ちゃんと繋いでて
Hold on tight.
簡単じゃない
It's not easy.
ゴールの影絵は
The shadow of the goal...
いつの日か届くかなって
...I wonder if I'll reach it someday.
支えてくれる
You support me.
ずっと
Always.
こだましてみるよ
I'll try to make it echo.
みんな一緒にせーの！
Everyone together, ready set go!
La la la...
うまくいかない時だって
Even when things don't go well,
直球ルート
a direct route,
明日の教科書
tomorrow's textbook.
水に流したら　何だってやれそうだ
If we wash it away, feels like we can do anything.
落書きの
Inside the doodles...
中光ってた想いを
...the feelings were shining.
君とこうして話せたなんて
That I could talk with you like this...
嘘みたいだな　もっと
...feels like a lie. More!
また書いて消して
Writing again and erasing.
みんな行くよ！せーの！
Everyone, let's go! Ready, set, go!
奇跡の空！
Miraculous Sky (Sora)!
おはよう こんにちはも ご挨拶
Good morning, hello, and greetings too.
ってあれ？ 嘘 もうこんな時間？
Wait, huh? No way, is it already this time?
午後から予定あるのに
I have plans starting in the afternoon,
すぐに支度をしなきゃ
I have to get ready right away.
行ってきます！
I'm off!
慌てて飛び出して気付く
I rush out in a panic and realize,
こっちじゃない そこだと
It's not this way, it's over there!
駆けて行きます
I'm running there!
トラブルばっか 転んで起きての
It's nothing but trouble, falling down and getting up,
毎日です
that's my everyday life.
なんでも思い通りとか
Having everything go exactly as planned,
そんな美味しい話はないけど
there's no such lucky story like that.
心の曇り空
But the cloudy skies of my heart,
晴らす合言葉
with a password to clear them up,
唱えて
chant it out,
ほら 快晴でしょ
look, it's clear weather!
ずっと！
Always!
みんなに届けたい
I want to reach everyone,
歌もダンスも元気も
my songs, my dance, and my energy!
きっと同じ空の下
Surely under the same sky,
笑顔も分け合えるよ
we can share our smiles too.
ちょっと疲れちゃう時も
Even when you get a little tired,
涙が出そうな時も
or when tears are about to fall,
いつも魔法の言葉で 今日も
always use the magic words, today too.
ケセラセラだから
Because it's Que Sera Sera,
さあ 絆 奏でて
come on, let's play the melody of our bond!
High! High! High!...
みんな 今日も一日頑張ろう
Everyone, let's do our best today too!
カメラにマイクに よし準備OK
Camera, mic, alright preparations OK!
お水もちゃんとあるし
I have my water too,
備えさえあれば憂いなし ね
if you're prepared, there's no worry, right?
それじゃ今日は何をしようかな
So then, what shall we do today?
お歌に雑談に あ ほらこれだね
Singing, chatting... Ah, look, this is it!
みんなと笑い飛ばせば
If I laugh it off with everyone,
また明日も晴れ渡る
tomorrow will be clear and sunny again!
よっしゃ！
Alright!
みんな声出して！
Everyone, shout it out!
ホッとため息こぼして
Breathing a sigh of relief,
ふと夜空を見上げたら
when I suddenly looked up at the night sky,
パッと満点の星たちが
suddenly a perfect score of stars,
キラキラ瞬いてた
were twinkling brightly.
ずっと！
Forever!
追いかけ続けたい
I want to keep chasing after it,
今日より高い夢でも
even if the dream is higher than today.
もっと強く羽ばたいて
Flapping my wings more strongly,
空まで駆けていくよ
I will run all the way to the sky.
そっと背中押すような
Like gently pushing my back,
温もり見つけたから
because I found that warmth.
いつまでもそばにいるよ
I will be by your side forever,
今日も！
today!
明日も！
and tomorrow!
ずっと！
Always!
ケセラセラだから
Because it's Que Sera Sera,
さあ 絆 奏でて
come on, let's play the melody of our bond!
High! High! High!...
みんな... みんな...
Everyone... Everyone...
新年！明けまして おめでとうございます！
Happy New Year!
本日は お寒い中 ありがとうございます
Thank you for coming today in this cold weather.
みんな来れた？
Did you all make it here?
あ 来れてるからいるのわかってる
Ah, you're here so I know you made it.
あの ちゃんと安全に来れましたか？
Um, did you make it here safely?
え 今回のソラパは
So, this time's Sorapa is,
私のライブ史上 最大規模ということで
the largest scale live performance in my history,
すごいおっきな会場で
at such a huge venue.
あの ハッシュタグとかも見てたんだけど 「でっか！」って
I was looking at the hashtags and people were saying "Huge!"
「でかいな すごいな」って書いてる人がいっぱいいて
There were lots of people writing "It's huge, it's amazing".
私も「でかいな すごいな」って思いながら見てました
I was also watching while thinking "It's huge, it's amazing".
リハーサルの時は ここにいっぱいそらともさん来るねって言われて
During rehearsal, I was told "lots of Soratomos will come here",
え 誰もいないじゃん！
and I was like "Eh, nobody's here!"
誰もいないよ！ 誰もいない！
Nobody's here! Nobody's here!
っていう会話をしながら
While having that conversation,
とても楽しくやっておりました
we were doing it very happily.
でもみんないるね！ ありがとう！
But everyone is here! Thank you!
というわけで 今日初めてライブだよって人！
So, who is here for their first live today?
おお 結構いるね
Oh, quite a few.
じゃあ 現地自体初めてだよって人
Then, who is at a venue for the first time?
結構いる！ ありがとう
Quite a few! Thank you.
じゃあ 頑張って あの手振るだけでいいからね
Then, do your best... just waving your hand is fine.
あの 女の子！
Um... Girls!
おお！ 声出してくれてありがとう 「きゃー」って聞こえた
Oh! Thanks for shouting. I heard "Kyaa!".
可愛い！ 大好き！
Cute! I love you!
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
え これってペンライトとかできるのかな？
Eh, can we do the penlight thing?
あ できないのかな？
Ah, maybe we can't?
こちらの人 赤！
People on this side, Red!
こちらの人は 青！
People on this side, Blue!
真ん中は 黄色！
The middle is Yellow!
こんな感じでですね
Just like this...
今日はペンライトでも遊べちゃうということで
Since we can play with penlights today,
ぜひぜひみんなでも楽しんでいきましょう
let's all have fun together!
今日はみんなも主役だよ！
Today, everyone is the main character too!
お水かわいい！
Drinking water is cute!
ありがとう
Thank you.
もうちょっと飲む
I'll drink a little more.
まだ飲んでない！
I haven't drunk it yet!
すぐお水だって分かったじゃん
You knew it was water right away.
後ろ向いたから？
Because I turned around?
えへへ、ありがとう
Ehehe, thank you.
さあ、というわけでね
Well then...
今日はいかがだったでしょうかとはいかないので
I can't exactly ask "how was it today?" just yet,
始まったばっかり！
because it just started!
なんですが！
However!
なんと... もう言っていいのかな？
Surprisingly... is it okay to say it already?
YouTubeの配信は...
The YouTube stream is...
なんと...
actually...
ここまでなんです
ending here.
分かってるばっかり！
You all know it already!
でも続き見たい人は...
But for those who want to see the rest...
どこだここ... ここら辺に...
where is it... somewhere around here...
からあのチケットが...
the tickets...
買うって言い方やだ
I don't like saying "buy".
見に来てね！
Come watch!
というわけで、先にどんどん行ってみましょうか！
So with that, let's keep moving forward!
盛り上がれますか！？
Are you ready to get hyped!?
楽しんでいってよ！
Let's have some fun!
それでは盛り上がっていこうよ！
Alright then, let's get exciting!
Oki Doki
冒頭無料配信はこちらで終了です。
The free introductory stream ends here.